<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thesis on void?</title><link>https://netotz.github.io/tags/thesis/</link><description>Recent content in thesis on void?</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://netotz.github.io/tags/thesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The process of designing a new algorithm</title><link>https://netotz.github.io/posts/a-fvs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netotz.github.io/posts/a-fvs/</guid><description>Introduction Earlier in the year I wrote about how the objective function of an optimization problem is decomposed and partially evaluated so an algorithm that uses that function runs faster. I found this technique so interesting that I tried to explain it in that post. But the goal wasn&amp;rsquo;t to just understand the decomposing of an objective function. I needed to design a fast algorithm to solve the $\alpha$-neighbor $p$-center problem (ANPCP), as I mentioned in the other post, and while researching to do so, I came across the concept of the fast interchange or fast swap and how it was applied to other location problems (not the ANPCP).</description></item><item><title>Decomposing an objective function</title><link>https://netotz.github.io/posts/decomposing-of/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netotz.github.io/posts/decomposing-of/</guid><description>As the thesis for the BSc Software Engineering, I&amp;rsquo;m researching heuristic algorithms in the Operations Research field. Specifically, my mentor and I are implementing heuristics for the $\alpha$-neighbor $p$-center problem (ANPCP for short). Because the literature about it is scarce, we&amp;rsquo;ve been reading papers that use heuristic algorithms for similar problems, and trying to adapt them to the ANPCP. In this process, I found it interesting how some authors decompose the objective function of a problem and evaluate it step by step while, at the same time, applying a heuristic to the current solution.</description></item></channel></rss>